4ormat.com 2019-06-01

# Privacy Policy | Format

Effective as of May 24, 2018 

This is the Privacy Policy of the format.com website (and any successor or other domains that we operate) and all content, services and products, including our mobile applications, that we provide (collectively, the “Application”). The Application is owned and operated by Ideaform Inc. (together with our affiliates and subsidiaries, “Ideaform”, “we”, “us”, “our” and terms of similar meaning). It describes the personal information that we collect from users of our Application as part of the normal operation of our Application, and how we use and disclose this information. Capitalized terms used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings in our Terms of Service. 

In this Privacy Policy, when we refer to “Users”, we mean our customers who use our Services to create their own Portfolios, and when we refer to “End Users” we mean the users, visitors and customers of our Users’ Portfolios. 

This Privacy Policy describes what we do with personal information that we collect and use for our own purposes (i.e., where we are a controller), such as User Account information and information about how you use and interact with our Services, including information you submit to our customer support as well as certain information relating to our Users’ End Users. 

We host and process Content for our Users, for their own use and for the use of their End Users. Our Users tell us what to do with their Content in relation to the Service, and in accordance with the Agreement and the operation of our Service we follow their instructions. This Privacy Policy does not describe what we do with Content on our Users’ instructions (i.e., as their processor). If you are an End User of one of our Users’ Portfolios and want to know how that User handles your information, you should check its privacy policy. If you want to know about what we do for our own purposes, read on. If you are a User, see our Data Processing Policy to learn more about how we process User Content on your instructions or with your permission. 

We use cookies and similar technologies. Our Cookie Policy describes what we do in that regard. 

By accepting this Privacy Policy in registration or by using our Services, you expressly consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to our Terms of Service. 

### How We Use Your Information

We use personal information in the file we maintain about you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on the Application, to provide to you the services offered by the Application; resolve service disputes; troubleshoot problems; measure consumer interest in our products and services; inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, events and updates; deliver information to you that, in some cases, is relevant to your interests, such as product news; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our Terms of Service; provide you with system or administrative messages, and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection. 

We may also use personal information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to analyze Application usage, to improve our content and product offerings, and to customize the Application's content, layout, and services. These uses improve the Application and better tailor it to meet your needs, so as to provide you with a smooth, efficient, safe and customized experience while using the Application. 

Please see below under “How we Retain your Personal Information” for information on what we do to account information when you terminate your account with us. 

### What Information Do We Collect?

Our primary purpose in collecting personal information from you is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. This allows us to provide services and features that most likely meet your needs, and to customize our service to make your experience safer and easier. We only collect personal information about you that we consider necessary for achieving this purpose. 

In general, you can browse the Application without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Once you become a User, we require you to provide various contact and identity information and other personal information as indicated on the relevant forms on the Application, and you are no longer anonymous to us. Where possible, on these forms we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. In addition, as you use the Application, you can from time to time enter or send to us personal information. 

You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to become a User or by not using the particular feature of the Application for which the information is being collected. 

We also automatically track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on our Application. We use this information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand, protect and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our Application or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our Application or not), your computer browser information, your IP address and your location. 

If you are an End User of our Users’ Portfolios, we also get information about your interactions with their Portfolios, though we use this in anonymous, aggregated or pseudonymized form which does not focus on you individually. We use this data to evaluate, provide, protect or improve our Services (including by developing new products and services). 

Some of this information is collected automatically using cookies and similar technologies when you use our Services and our Users’ Portfolios. We let our Users control what cookies and similar technologies are used through their Portfolios (except those we need to use to provide the Services properly, such as for performance or security related reasons). You can read more about our use of cookies in our Cookie Policy. Some of this information is similarly collected automatically through your browser or from your device. 

We also use Twitter’s Conversion Tracking and Tailored Audiences product - by using the Application you are permitting Twitter to collect non-identifying data for analytics purposes. We use this data to improve upon our services and audience; this anonymous data is only used to understand our user base and to assess features and potential advertising content to enhance the Application experience. At no point in time is your personal information tied to this analytics data by Twitter. More information about how you can opt out of this program, including through the Do Not Track functionality in your web browser, is available [here](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405). 

If you use a Third Party Service (such as Google) to register for an Account, the Third Party Service may provide us with your Third Party Service account information on your behalf, such as your name and email address (we don’t store passwords you use to access Third Party Services). Your privacy settings on the Third Party Service normally control what they share with us. Make sure you are comfortable with what they share by reviewing their privacy policies and, if necessary, modifying your privacy settings directly on the Third Party Service. 

We do not collect or save your credit card information when you use your credit card to subscribe to our Application - when you subscribe to our Application, the payment processors that we use handle all credit card information. However, If you subscribe, we do obtain limited information about your payment card from our payment processors, such as the last four digits, the country of issuance and the expiration date. Currently, our payment processors are Braintree, PayPal and Bambora. Please consult their terms of use and privacy policies for more information about they use your personal information. 

Following your registration on the Application, you can review and change your information in your account area. If you disclose personal information on the Application and wish to have it removed, please contact us at the support contact information posted on the Application. 

### Our Disclosure of Your Information

We will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties without your explicit consent. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed in the normal scope of business to provide our services: 

**Anonymized Aggregated Data.** We aggregate and anonymize data and use and disclose such information for a variety of purposes. However, in these situations, we do not disclose any information that could be used to identify you personally. 

**End Users.** We may share with our Users data regarding usage by End Users of their Portfolios. For example, we may provide a User with information about what web page the End User visited before coming to their Portfolios and how their End Users interacted with their Portfolios. This is so Users can analyze the usage of their Portfolios and improve their services. 

**Public Areas of the Application.** All of your activities in the public areas of the Application will be identifiable to your User ID, and other people can see your published content. 

**Subsidiaries and Affiliates; Service Providers.** We may from time to time use the services of affiliates, subsidiaries and unrelated service providers in the operation of the Application, and may disclose personal information to them in the course of our use of their services. For example, we may use the services of third-party hosting companies to host the operation of the Application. This may involve the hosting of data, including personal information, on servers operated by those hosting companies. We also partner with third party publishers, advertising networks and service providers to manage our ads on other sites. Our third party partners may set cookies on your device or browser to gather information about your activities on the Services and other sites you visit, in order to provide you with Ideaform ads. For example, if you visit Ideaform and also use a social media platform, you may see a Ideaform ad in your social media newsfeed or timeline. See our Cookie Policy for more information. We take care to use only service providers that we believe are reputable and able to live up to our and your expectations, including about the handling of confidential information. 

**Legal Requests; Emergencies; Jurisdictions.** We cooperate with law enforcement inquiries and demands for information that are made under force of law. We are also cognizant of the need to address emergencies. Therefore, we may disclose User and End User personal information (a) to any governmental authority as part of an investigation to determine our compliance with any applicable law, rule, or regulation (including privacy laws, rules, and regulations), (b) in response to a court order, subpoena, discovery request, or other lawful judicial or administrative proceeding, (c) as otherwise required under any applicable law, rule, or regulation, and (d) in good faith, to protect or defend our rights or property or those of other users or End Users. 

We may also disclose personal information to the acquiror or its agents in the course of the sale of our business. If we do this, the disclosure will be subject to confidentiality arrangements customary in such transactions. 

### Security

Ideaform Inc. strives to protect your personal information. For security of transactions, we use the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts any personal information you enter into registration forms on the Application. The encryption process protects your information, by scrambling it before it is sent to us from your computer. We also make commercially reasonable effort to ensure the security of your personal information on our system. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. 

### How We Retain Your Personal Information

We retain personal information regarding you or your use of the Services for as long as your Account is active or for as long as needed to provide you or our Users with the Services. We also retain personal information for as long as necessary to achieve the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, for example, to comply with our legal obligations, to protect us in the event of disputes and to enforce our agreements and to protect our and others’ interests. 

The precise periods for which we keep your personal information vary depending on the nature of the information and why we need it. Factors we consider in determining these periods include the minimum required retention period prescribed by law or recommended as best practice, the period during which a claim can be made with respect to an agreement or other matter, whether the personal information has been aggregated or pseudonymized, and other relevant criteria. For example, the period we keep your email address is connected to how long your Account is active, while the period for which we keep a support message is based on how long has passed since the last submission in the thread. 

As Users may come back to us after an Account becomes inactive, we don’t immediately delete your personal information when a trial period expires or you cancel all paid Services. Instead, we keep your personal information for a reasonable period of time, so it will be there for you if you come back. 

You may delete your Account by contacting us at [privacy@format.com](mailto:privacy@format.com) and we will delete the personal information it holds about you (unless we need to retain it for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy). 

Please note that in the course of providing the Services, we collect and maintain aggregated, anonymized or de-personalized information which we may retain indefinitely. 

### Other Information Collectors

Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. To the extent that you disclose your information to other parties through the Application, including Third Party Services, different rules may apply to their use, collection and disclosure of the personal information you disclose to them. Since we do not control the information use, collection or disclosure policies of third parties, you are subject to their privacy policies. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your personal information to others. 

### End Users’ Personal Information

Users who have created a Portfolio using the Services are responsible for what they do with the personal information they collect, directly or through our Services, about their End Users.  This section is directed to our Users concerning their End Users. 

  1. #### Your Relationship with End Users

If you’re one of our Users, you may collect personal information about your End Users. For example, during an eCommerce checkout you may ask your End Users to provide their name, address, email address and payment information so that you can complete their orders. You may also use cookies and similar technologies to analyze usage and other trends. 

You're solely responsible for complying with any laws and regulations that apply to your collection and use of your End Users’ information, including personal information you collect about them from us or using our functionality or cookies or similar technologies. 

You must publish your own privacy and cookie policy and comply with them.   
We’re not liable for your relationship with your End Users or how you collect and use personal information about them (even if you collect it from us or using our functionality or cookies or similar technologies) and we won’t provide you with any legal advice regarding such matters. 

  2. #### End User Payment Information

Your End Users’ payment information may be processed via third party eCommerce Payment Processors with which you integrate your Account, in accordance with such eCommerce Payment Processors’ terms and policies. We transmit your End Users’ complete payment information when they initially provide or update it only so that we can pass it along to the eCommerce Payment Processors you agree to use. We don’t collect or store your End Users’ payment information except as described above. 

### Your Rights and Choices

Where applicable law requires (and subject to any relevant exceptions under law), you may have the right to access, update, change or delete personal information. 

You can access, update, change or delete personal information (or that of your End Users) either directly in your Account or by contacting us at [privacy@format.com](mailto:privacy@format.com) to request the required changes. You can exercise your other rights (including deleting your Account) by contacting us at the same email address. 

You can also elect not to receive marketing communications by changing your preferences in your Account or by following the unsubscribe instruction in such communications. 

Please note that, for technical reasons, there is likely to be a delay in deleting your personal Information from our systems when you ask us to delete it. We also will retain personal Information in order to comply with the law, protect our and others’ rights, resolve disputes or enforce our legal terms or policies, to the extent permitted under applicable law. 

You may have the right to restrict or object to the processing of your personal information or to exercise a right to data portability under applicable law. You also may have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority, subject to applicable law. If you are subject to EU data protection laws, we suggest you lodge any such complaints with our lead supervisory authority: 

Irish Data Protection Commissioner   
Office of the Data Protection Commissioner   
Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co. Laois, R32 AP23, Ireland   
Phone +353 57 868 4757   
Fax: +353 57 868 4757   
Email: [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie)

Additionally, if we rely on consent for the processing of your personal information, you have the right to withdraw it at any time and free of charge. When you do so, this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent withdrawal. 

Our Cookie Policy explains how you can manage cookies and similar technologies. 

If you are an End User of one of our Users’ Portfolios, you should contact them to exercise your rights with respect to any information they hold about you. 

### Data Transfers

Personal information that you submit through the Services may be transferred to countries other than where you live, such as, for example, to servers in the United States. We also store personal information locally on the devices you use to access the Services. 

Your personal information may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. 

In such cases, we continue to protect the information with appropriate safeguards, but it may be subject to the legal jurisdiction of those countries and governmental authorities in those countries. 

**Questions?**

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand.   
If you have questions, concerns or if you would like more detailed information, please email our privacy officer at [privacy@format.com](mailto:privacy@format.com).
